What are the top three programming
languages that you think you know every
engineer should learn in 2026 to kind of
become better at programming?
>> Haskell.
I think it's a
it's incredible language if it has
everything you need to
really learn about functional
programming.
I think one of the main benefits is much
there is a old joke
seen in the Haskell community that
if you write a program in in
Haskell and in C
in C
really spend one week
to make it efficient
and then you spend one year to make it
correct.
In Haskell you spend one week to make it
correct and then you may spend one year
to make it efficient.
Again, that's not my joke but
I it has some truth not
always true etc. but I think it gives
the the idea. I think this is
maybe the the the main the most
important lesson of Haskell. But Haskell
has many other
valid the the thing about type inference
for instance that I mean the entire
language is built is
types are optional everywhere and yet it
can do type inference for everything it
can infer the types correctly etc.
C or some
low language I mean you can also have a
to learn some assembler or to to see you
but assemblers now are becoming too much
complex. It would be to learn like the
the 8080 assembler very old assembler of
a very
but to have this exactly this idea of
what a machine does how it does stuff at
exactly the basic level. So, I have this
understanding. Scheme is a language that
I like very much because of this exactly
this economy of of ideas. Very very few
concepts and it can do some amazing
things with the
with very few concepts. One language
that this very very very old, but it I
still think it is Snowball.
It was the I think it was the first
languages to have pattern matching and
this idea of doing a I mean it's really
strong patterns, etc. And I think it's
sometimes it's it's interesting to see
old languages because exactly nowadays a
lot of language tend to like I said the
zero indexing that people
they copy but a lot they they tend to be
too uniform in some aspects and so so
it's interesting to see some older
languages that have some ideas that may
maybe not even good ideas, but it's
really interesting.